Antonio De Blasi

Software Engineer @ Credit Suisse

toni.deblasi@gmail.com

Summary

Software Engineer with over 15 years long professional experience in the analysis, design and development of complex enterprise software systems, in the Banking and Telecommunications areas, for major companies in the market. Currently working for and focused on the finance industry. Lifelong learner.

Experience

C++ Senior Software Engineer at Credit Suisse giugno 2017 - Present

C++ Senior Software Engineer at Credit Suisse (Contractor) aprile 2012 - Present

Software Consultant

- Main activities: Credit Risk Management methodologies and core infrastructure design and implementation.
- Languages, frameworks and tools: C++, Python, UML, SQL, Unix, Linux, Sybase, Subversion, Eclipse

C++ Senior Software Engineer settembre 2007 - marzo 2012 (4 anni 7 mesi)

- Main activity: R&D in the telecommunications area: value added telecommunication systems, traffic billing system, traffic quality analysis and reporting applications, call routing algorithms, mobile applications
- Languages, frameworks and tools: C/C++, Python, Objective C, UML, SQL, Javascript, Html5, JQuery, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, XCode, Eclipse. Boost, Loki, Log4cxx, CppUnit, gSoap, Cocoa Touch, Red5, TCP/IP, Posix Threads, SOAP and REST web services, Subversion

Java/J2EE Software Engineer at ObjectWay aprile 2006 - agosto 2007 (1 anno 5 mesi)

- Main activity: Java/J2EE development of enterprise applications in the banking area

- Languages, frameworks and tools: Java/J2EE, Struts, Tomcat, Spring, Xml, Sql, Hibernate, Ibatis, Uml, Soap, Oracle, Eclipse, JUnit, Log4J, Toad, Subversion, ClearCase.

C++ Software Engineer at ObjectWay

febbraio 2001 - aprile 2006 (5 anni 3 mesi)

- Main activity: analysis, design and development of a toolset (client/server Unix/Oracle environment) for the 'operation&maintenance' management of GSM and UMTS radio mobile networks based on Siemens network devices.
- Languages, frameworks and tools: UML, C++, Pro C, Java/J2EE, Sql, stl, Boost, Loki, Cppunit, Log4cxx, Doxygen, Sun Workshop, Eclipse, Rational Rose, ClearCase, Oracle

C++ Senior Software Engineer at ObjectWay

novembre 1999 - febbraio 2001 (1 anno 4 mesi)

- Main activity: collaboration to the design and development of an application for the management of clients portfolio, used by financial promoters of RAS insurance company.
- Languages, frameworks and tools: UML, C++, stl, Borland vcl, Borland C++ Builder, Rational Rose, Pvcs, Sysbase

Education

Università di Pisa

Master's Degree, Computer Engineering, Computer Engineering, 1989 - 1999

Antonio De Blasi

Software Engineer @ Credit Suisse

toni.deblasi@gmail.com



Contact Antonio on LinkedIn